<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[CodeCrunch.io]]></title>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://codecrunch.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-17T11:59:16.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://codecrunch.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tobias Hale]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[thale.android@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Welcome To CodeCrunch]]></title>
    <link href="http://codecrunch.io/2015/10/16/AboutMe/"/>
    <id>http://codecrunch.io/2015/10/16/AboutMe/</id>
    <published>2015-10-16T19:10:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-17T11:59:16.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to CodeCrunch.io, this is my personal blogging website where I will write guides, fixes<br>and any issues that I have found as a developer.<br>I started web development in June 2014 and I have learnt so much in that time and I found<br>reading blog posts, articles and stack overflow to be a huge part of my learning process.<br>Now that I am working fulltime at a digital agency in London I thought it would<br>be a good time for me to write some posts about the problems that I come across in my day to day<br>life as a developer (there are many!) and hopefully developers new and experienced can learn something<br>from my posts. I primarily work with Ruby on Rails and AngularJs, so the majority of my posts<br>will focus around these, but I will be teaching myself Node fairly soon.</p>
<p>I hope you enjoy this blog and any feedback would be great. If you want to ask me any questions<br>then just leave comments below or you can follow me on Twitter: @ThatTobMate</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Welcome to CodeCrunch.io, this is my personal blogging website where I will write guides, fixes<br>and any issues that I have found as a ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
